Allan Ludwig Photograph Collection: New England Gravestones
Yale University Arts Library
Allan Ludwig Photograph Collection: New England Gravestones
1966-
VRC 301
Yale University Arts Library
0.54
1 box
Photographs related to the publication: Ludwig, Allan I. Graven images: New England stone-carving and its symbols, 1650-1815 / by Allan I. Ludwig. Middletown, Conn.: Wesleyan University Press [c1966] xxxi, 482 p.: ill., maps; 26 cm.
Ludwig, Allan I.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Photographs related to the publication: Ludwig, Allan I. Graven images: New England stone-carving and its symbols, 1650-1815 / by Allan I. Ludwig. Middletown, Conn.: Wesleyan University Press [c1966] xxxi, 482 p.: ill., maps; 26 cm.
Folders 1 and 2: 150 black and white photographs, each photograph numbered in pencil on the reverse corresponding to enclosed inventory. List of illustrations enclosed: The following items are missing (2007), numbers: 8, 13, 18, 29, 38, 41, 42, 46, 47, 54, 55, 57, 63, 72, 83, 84, 85, 86, 87, 88, 91, 92, 93, 94, 96, 99, 100, 102, 103, 107, 115, 118, 119, 124, 127, 128, 132, 136, 139, 140, 141, 144, 145, 147, 150, 155, 156, 157, 159, 168a-c, 170a-b, 171b-d, 172a-d, 173a-d, 174a-b, 175a-b, 176, 177a-b, 179, 180, 181a-c, 182c, 183b.
Folder 3: 55 photographs not used in the author's 1966 edition of Graven images: New England stone-carving and its symbols, 1650-1815. Numbered in pencil on reverse keyed to enclosed inventory; 15 items labeled in pencil with location and carver's signature on reverse. List of illustrations enclosed for items 1-45: The following items are missing (2007), numbers: 19, 21.
Arrangement
3 folders of unmounted, unlabelled black and white photographs.
Sepulchral monuments -- New England; Sculpture, American -- New England; Stone carving -- New England; Photographs; Reproductions; Graven images: New England stone-carving and its symbols, 1650-1815
- Betsey Tracy stone, 1792, Norwichtown, CT, Granite (Box 1)
- Susanna Jayne stone, 1776, Marblehead, MA, Slate,detail (Box 1)
- Pomber childrenstone, 1773, Franklin, CT, Granite (Box 1)
- Latiner child stone, 1789, Bloomfield, CT, Redstone (Box 1)
- William Dickson stone, 1692, Cambridge, MA, Slate, 28.5 x 20.5, detail (Box 1)
- John Watson stone, 1678, Cambridge, MA, Slate, 24.5 x 22.5 (Box 1)
- Jacob Elliot stone, 1693, the Granary, Boston, MA, Slate, detail (Box 1)
- John Hurd stone, 1784, the Granary, Boston, MA, Slate (Box 1)
- Martha Welch stone, 1775, Storrs, CT, Granite, 35.5 x 58.5 (Box 1)
- Captain Samuel Dwight stone, 1763, Enfield, CT, Redstone, 29 x 38 (Box 1)
- Sarah Swan stone, 1767, Bristol, RI, Slate, detail (Box 1)
- Joseph Tapping stone, 1678, King's Chapel, Boston, MA, Slate (Box 1)
- Rebekah Gerrish stone, 1743, King's Chapel, Boston, MA, Slate, detail (Box 1)
- William Williams stone, 1743, East Hartford, CT, Redstone, 21 x 24.5, detail (Box 1)
- Henry Roby stone, 1807, Copp's Hill, Boston, MA, Slate, detail (Box 1)
- Nathaniel Jackson stone, 1743, Plymouth, MA, Slate, 25.5 x 27, detail (Box 1)
- Thomas Kendel, ca. 1678, Wakefield, MA, Slate, 21 3/4 x 25 (Box 1)
- Mary Harris stone, 1744, Providence, RI, N.U., 16.5 x 18, Detail (Box 1)
- William Dickson stone, Cambridge, MA, Slate, 284.5 x 20.5, detail (Box 1)
- Zachariah Long stone, 1668, Charlestown, MA, Slate, 18.5 x 22.5, detail (Box 1)
- Rev. Jonathan Pierpoint stone, 1709, Wakefield, MA, Slate, 30 x 27 (Box 1)
- Thomas Faunce stone, 1745, Plymouth, MA, Slate, 22 3/4 x 32, detail (Box 1)
- Nathaniel Jackson stone, 1743, Plymouth, MA, Slate, 25.5 x 27, detail (Box 1)
- Elizabeth Bradford stone, 1741, Kingston, MA, Slate, 17 x 16 3/4, detail (Box 1)
- Margarit Cumings stone, 1790, Billerica, MA, Slate, 23.5 x 29.5, detail (Box 1)
- Elizabeth Clark stone, 1767, Chelsford, MA, Slate, detail (Box 1)
- Major Jonathan Allen stone, 1780, Northampton, MA, Redstone, 29 3/4 x 49, detail (Box 1)
- Sarah Allen stone, 1785, Bristol, RI, Schist, detail (Box 1)
- The Holmes children stone, 1795, East Glastonbury, CT, Redstone, detail (Box 1)
- Daniel Squier stone, 1783, Franklin, CT, Granite, detail (Box 1)
- Pamela Munro stone, 1776, Lexington, MA, Slate, 15 x 21, detail (Box 1)
- Ephraim Walker stone,1777, Brookfield, MA, Quartzite, detail (Box 1)
- Deberoh Samson stone, 1769, Kingston, MA, Slate, 24 x 27 1/4, detail (Box 1)
- Elizabeth Norton, 1751, Durham, CT, Redstone, 29 1/4 x 45.5 (Box 1)
- Submit Gaylord stone, 1766, Hadley, MA, Redstone, 29 1/4 x 45.5, detail (Box 1)
- Camp family stone, 1767, Durham, CT, Redstone, 28.5 x 53.5, detail (Box 1)
- Mercy Buliod stone, 1771, Newport, RI, Slate, signed by John Stevens, Jr., detail (Box 1)
- Roger Huntington stone, 1785, Lebanon, CT, N.U., 17 x 27, detail (Box 1)
- Dorothy Walker stone, 1804, Brookfield, MA, Quartzite, 24 x 33, detail (Box 1)
- John Cleverly stone, 1705, Quincy, MA, Slate, signed by J.N., Detail. (Box 1)
- Manning Children stone, 1750, Norwichtown, CT, Granite, 28.5 x 49, detail (Box 1)
- Isaac Williams stone, 1781, Tolland, CT, Redstone, detail (Box 1)
- Gamaliel Ripley stone, 1799, Scotland, CT, Granite, 29 3/4 x 42, detail (Box 1)
- Thomas Drury stone, 1778, Auburn, MA, Slate (Box 1)
- Danniel Weaver stone, 1801, Rockingham, VT, slate, detail (Box 1)
- Neal Family stone, ca. 1678, the Cranary, Boston, MA, slate. (Box 1)
- Sarah Johnson stone, 1790, Durham, CT, Redstone, 34.5 x 67 (Box 1)
- Rev. Abraham Nott stone, 1756, Essex, CT, Redstone, detail. (Box 1)
- Martha Green stone, 1770, Harvard, MA, slate, 27 x 37, detail (Box 1)
- Mary Gargill stone, 1813, Palmer Center, MA, marble, 32 x 38, detail (Box 1)
- Eunice Colton stone, 1763, Longmeadow, MA, Redstone, 22 x 36 3/4, detail (Box 1)
- Ruth Carter stone, 1697/8, the Granary, Boston, MA, slate (Box 1)
- Mary Brown stone, 1782, Plymouth, MA, slate, 16 3/4 x 23, detail (Box 1)
- Deacon Thomas Davis stone, ca. 1760, Oxford, MA, slate, detail (Box 1)
- Mary Bliss stone, 1757, Longmeadow, MA, slate, 25.5 x 27, detail. (Box 1)
- Nathaniel Jackson stone, 1743, Plymouth, MA, slate, 25.5 x 27, detail of border panel (Box 1)
- Tufts stone, 1703, Malden, MA, slate, detail of Border panel. (Box 1)
- Rebekah Bunker stone, 1710, Cambridge, MA, slate, 19 x 16.5, detail of border panel (Box 1)
- Nicholas Larrance stone, 1710, Charlestown, Ma, slate, 26 x 19, detail of border panel (Box 1)
- Deacon Joseph West stone, 1764, Tolland, CT, Redstone 25 x 49, detail (Box 1)
- Deacon Matthew Rockwell, 1782, South Windsor, CT, Redstone, 24.5 x 43, detail. (Box 1)
- Samuel Hinckley stone, 1792, Brookfield, MA, marble, 22.5 x 37, detail (Box 1)
- Deacon Jonathan Smith stone, 1774, Hadley, MA, Redstone, 22 x 33, detail (Box 1)
- Mary Hinckley stone, 1792, Brookfield, MA, marble, 21.5 x 35, detail (Box 1)
- Pamber stone, 1783, Franklin, CT, Granite, detail (Box 1)
- Eliakim Hayden stone, 1797, Essex, CT, Redstone. (Box 1)
- The Lane Family stone, 1791, Rockingham, VT, slate, detail (Box 1)
- Anna Webb stone, 1805, Scotlan, CT, Granite, 30 3/4 x 60, detail (Box 1)
- Hannah Huntington stone, 1746, Norwichtown, CT, M.U., 30 3/4 x 32.5, detail (Box 1)
- Jonas Clark stone, 1770, Chelmsford, MA, slate, detail (Box 1)
- Christiana Cook stone, 1796, Kingston, MA, slate, 27.5 x 42.5, detail (Box 1)
- Charles Bardin stone, 1773, Newport, RI, slate, detail (Box 1)
- Betsy Shaw stone, 1795, Plymouth, MA, slate, 22.5 x 36, detail (Box 1)
- Samuel Ruggles stone, 1749, Billerica, MA, slate. (Box 1)
- Stone dated 1732, Granite, Providence, RI (Box 1)
- Lucinda Day stone, 1800, Chester, VT, slate, detail. (Box 1)
- Whiting Family stone, 1781, Rockingham, VT, slate, detail. (Box 1)
- Robert Cleave stone, 1730, Portland, CT, Redstone, 18.5 x 23, detail (Box 1)
- Job Harris stone, 1729, Providence, RI, slate, 24.5 x 27 3/4, detail (Box 1)
- Nathan Lester stone, 1773, Pachaug, CT, Redstone, detail. (Box 1)
- Robert Cutlar stone, 1761, Brookfield, MA, slate, 30 x 27, detail (Box 1)
- Meriah Killborn stone, 1710, Rowley, MA, Schist, 17.5 x 15.5 (Box 1)
- Hunt child stone, 1797, Northampton, MA, marble, 22.5 x 37.5, detail (Box 1)
- William Kentfield stone, 1777, Belchertown, MA, Granite, 17 x 23.5, detail (Box 1)
- Sussana Scott stone, 1719, Rowley, MA, Schist, 21 x 23.5 (Box 1)
- Thomas Lovell stone, 1718, Ipswich, MA, Schist, detail (Box 1)
- Hulda Curtis stone, 1765, Stratford, CT, Redstone, 23.5 x 47, detail (Box 1)
- Abigail Merick stone, 1773, Glastonbury, CT, Granite, 26 x 48.5 (Box 1)
- Abigail Merick footstone, 1773, Glastonbury, CT, Granite, 18.5 x 24.5 (Box 1)
- Sarah Long stone, 1674, Charlestown, MA, slate, 27.5 x 24.5, detail (Box 1)
- Deacon Daniel House stone, 1762, East Glatonbury, CT, Redstone, 23.5 x 24 3/4, detail (Box 1)
- Wilborah Washbun stone, 1743, Kingston, MA, slate, 18.5 x 23.5, detail (Box 1)
- Esther Sampson stone, 1783, Kingston, MA, 19.5 x 29.5, detail (Box 1)
- Martha Fuller stone, 1785, Hebron, CT, Granite, 28 x 58 (Box 1)
- John Hurley stone, 1729, Haverhill, Ma, Schist. (Box 1)
- Sir Simon Baskerville Monument, Crypt, St. Paul's Cathedral, London, 1641, M.U. (Box 1)
- Console Bracket, South Door, St. Paul's Cathedral, London, detail (Box 1)
- Bridget Webb Monument, 1715, Stamford, England (Box 1)
- Sarah Herbert stone, 1710, Bury St. Edmonds, England. (Box 1)
- Stone dated 1732 from Thoray, Cambridgeshire, England (Box 1)
- South Frieze, St. Paul's Cathedral, London, England (Box 1)
- Emy Cary Tomb, 1756, Hampstead, St. Andrew's, London. (Box 1)
- JohnRehbury stone, 1690, Bury St. Edmonds, England (Box 1)
- Mary Hubbard stone, 171.., Bury St. Edmonds, England (Box 1)
- Elizabeth Stoakes stone, ca. 1730-1750, Bunhill Fields, London, England, detail (Box 1)
- Thomas and Mary Oldham stone, 1819, Thorney, Cambridgeshire, England (Box 1)
- Stone cut ca. 1770, Bunhill Fields, London, England (Box 1)
- Stone cut in the Mid-18th century from Thorney, Cambridgeshire, England, detail (Box 1)
- Jane Coe stone, 1816, Thorney, Cambridgeshire, England, detail (Box 1)
- Calvin Warner stone, 1853, Harvard, MA, marble, 23 3/4 x 45 3/4, detail (Box 1)
- The French stone, cut ca. 1760, Bunhill Fields, London, detail (Box 1)
- Sharman stone, 1833, Thorney, Cambridgeshire, England, detail (Box 1)
- Wallis stone, 1820, Soham, Cambridgeshire, England, detail (Box 1)
- William Sharman stone, 1807, Thorney, Cambridgeshire, England (Box 1)
- Ann Petterfor stone, 1774, Southwold, Suffolk, England (Box 1)
- Elizabeth Brown stone, 1773, Bunhill Fields, London, England, detail (Box 1)
- Detail of 18th century stone from Thorney, Cambridgeshire, England (Box 1)
- Detail of a mid-18th century stone from St. Andrew's, Hampstead, London (Box 1)
- Detail of late-18th century stone from Thorney, Cambridgeshire, England (Box 1)
- Flavell stone, 1790, Bunhill Fields, London, England (Box 1)
- Sarah... stone, 1707, Thorney, Cambridgeshire, England (Box 1)
- David Forbes stone, 1729, Windsor, CT, Redstone. (Box 1)
- Mary Greenhill stone, cut ca. 1690-1710, Shorn, Kent, England, detail (Box 1)
- Sarah Pimble stone, 1726, Linton, Herefs. England, courtesey F. Burgess (Box 1)
- William Sinclair stone, 1753, Spencer, MA, slate, 19.5 x 14, detail (Box 1)
- Broadside of George Cockayn, 1692, Printed in London (Box 1)
- Medieval mosaic from Rome. No futher information available. (Box 1)
- Joseph Tapping stone, 1678, King's Chapel, Boston, MA, slate, detail (Box 1)
- Hieroglyph from Francis Quarles Hieroglyphs of the Life of Man (London, 1638). Copy in the collection of the Society of Antiquaries, London, England (Box 1)
- Engraving by Charles Delaram after an original by Nicholas Hilliard (Box 1)
- Hannah Jackson stone, 1763, Plymouth, MA, M.U., 20 x 23, detail (Box 1)
- Frontispiece of Horae Lyricae by Isaac Watts published in London in 1727. Engraving cut in 1722. Collection of the author. (Box 1)
- John Watson stone, 1753, Plymouth, MA, slate, 27.5 x 33, detail (Box 1)
- Samuel Hall stone, 1795, Meriden, CT, Redstone, 24.5 x 33 3/4, detail (Box 1)
- Timothy Stone, A Sermon Preached Before His Excellency Samuel Huntington Esq. L.L.D. (Hartford, CT, 1792) collection of the author. (Box 1)
- Detail of the Broadside "On the Death of Five Young Men Who Was Murdered, " Mar. 5, 1770, now in the collection of the Massachusetts Historical Society. (Box 1)
- From a New England Prizer published in Haverhill, MA in 1811, now in the collection of Sterling Memorial Library, Yale University, New Haven, CT (Box 1)
- See No. 137 (Box 1)
- Ibid (Box 1)
- Ibid (Box 1)
- 18th century English Broadside reproduced in John W. Draper's, A Century of Broadside Elegies (London, 1928) (Box 1)
- Polly Harris stone, 1787, Charlestown, MA, slate, 22.5 x 24 3/4, detail (Box 1)
- Broadside cut for Rebekah Sewall, 1710, Now in the Collection of the Boston Public Library. (Box 1)
- Engraved cut from Isaac Watt's Horae Lyricae (London, 1727) p. A2. Collection of the Author. (Box 1)
- William Greenough stone, 1693, Copp's Hill, Boston, MA, slate. (Box 1)
- Benjamin Hills stone, 1683, The Granary, Boston, MA, slate (Box 1)
- Deacon John Hammond stone, 1713, Watertown, MA, slate (Box 1)
- Rebekah Row stone, 1682, Charlestown, MA, slate, 27.5 x 17 (Box 1)
- Elizabeth Codman stone, 1708, Charlestown, MA, slate, 23.5 x 16 3/4. (Box 1)
- see No. 20 (Box 1)
- Anna Barnard stone, 1774, Marblehead, MA, slate, detail (Box 1)
- Rev. William Whitwell stone, 1781, Marblehead, MA, slate, detail (Box 1)
- Lieut. John Hunt stone, 1716, Rumford, RI, slate (Box 1)
- Nathaniel Waldron stone, 1769, Newport, RI, slate, detail (Box 1)
- Elizabeth Coggeshall stone, 1773, Newport, RI, slate, detail (Box 1)
- Ursula McCurdy stone, 1781, Norwich, CT, slate, 24 x 37 (Box 1)
- Sary Brewster stone, 1773, Norwich, CT, Redstone, 14 x 22 (Box 1)
- Capt. Nathaniel Sutlief stone, 1760, Durham, CT, Redstone, 27 x 54 (Box 1)
- Rev. Samuel Woodbridge stone, 1746, East Hartford, CT, Redstone, 30 1/4 x 36 (Box 1)
- B&D. John Holmes stone, slate, Middleboro Center, MA, 1728, 18.5 x 19, details (Box 1)
- D. Sarah Hall stone, 1756, Kingston, MA, slate, 18 3/4 x 24, detail (Box 1)
- John White stone, 1668, Haverhill, MA, Schist (Box 1)
- C. Ruth Peaslee stone, 1723, Haverhill, MA, Chist, detail (Box 1)
- Nathaniel Peaslee stone, 1730, Haverhill, MA, Schist (Box 1)
- D. John Ropper stone, 1700, Ipswich, MA, Schist, 23.5 x 23.5, detail (Box 1)
- D. Mary Plats stone, 1726, Rowley, MA, Schist, 21 x 22, detail (Box 1)
- C. Mary Pickard stone, 1743, Rowley, MA, slate/schist, 24 3/4 x 24, detail (Box 1)
- C. Hannah Clark stone, 1739, Harvard, MA, slate/schist, 19 3/4 x 21.5, detail (Box 1)
- Samuel Green stone, 1759, Lexington, MA, slate, 27 3/4 x 33 3/4, detail (Box 1)
- C. Rebekah Worcester stone, 1772, Harvard, MA,slate, 21 3/4 x 31.5, detail (Box 1)
- D. Patience Hodsell stone, 1725, New London, CT, schist, 16.5 x 13.5, detail (Box 1)
- D. William Hall stone, 1727, Mansfield Center, CT, Granite, 19.5 x 19.5, detail (Box 1)
- D. Joshua Huntington stone, 1745, Norwichtown, CT, M.U., 34 3/4 x 44.5, detail (Box 1)
- B. Captain Humphrey Davenport stone, 1750, Conventry, CT, M.U., 33.5 x 21, detail (Box 1)
- B. Elizabeth Clark stone, 1769, Columbia, CT, Granite, detail (Box 1)
- Rufus Collins stone, 1790, Columbia, CT, marble, 20 3/4 x 27. (Box 1)
- B. Ann Dewey stone, 1768, Columbia, CT, Granite, 24.5 x 35.5, detail (Box 1)
- D. Katherine Rosseter, Durham, CT, Redstone, detail (Box 1)
- Lydia Phelps stone 1757, Hebron, CT, redstone, 29 x 50.5 (Box 1)
- Lydia Bennitt, 1791, Columbia, CT, marble, 20.5 x 31.5 (Box 1)
- C. Chloe Stoughton stone, 1769, Norwichtown, CT, Granite, 29 x 43, detail (Box 1)
- C.Huckens Storrs stone, 1784, Mansfield Center, CT, Granite, 29.5 x 50.5, detail (Box 1)
- B. Anna Webb stone, 1805, Scotland, CT, Granite, 30 3/4 x 60, detail (Box 1)
- B. Hannah Dwight stone, 1792, Belchertown, MA, Granite, 26.5 x 47, detail (Box 1)
- B. Artemas Lamb stone, 1791, Spencer, MA, Granite, 17.5 x 30, detail (Box 1)
- David Adams stone, 1790, Mansfield Center, CT, marble, 25 x 48, detail (Box 1)
- B. The Roger Huntington stone, 1785, Lebanon, CT, M.U., 17.5 x 27, detail (Box 1)
- Captain and Mrs .Pyam Blower stone, 1709, Cambridge, MA, 25 3/ 4 x 2 3/4, Slate. Attributed to Joseph Lamson of Charlestown, MA, One of the first three portrait-effigies to be carved on a New England gravestone and one of the earliest portraits of a woman. (Box 1)
- Detail of The Captain and Mrs .Pyam Blower stone. (Box 1)
- Detail of The Captain and Mrs .Pyam Blower stone. (Box 1)
- Deacon Thomas Barrett stone, 1799, Concord, MA, slate. Attributted to Daniel Hastings of Newton, MA. A late 18th century example of the provincial baroque portrait style favored in New England. (Box 1)
- James Foster stone, 1763, Dorchester, MA, slate. James Foster was probably a stone carver and this portrait may have been cut by his son. Notice the winding cloth over the shoulders of the figure. (Box 1)
- William Rogers stone, 1772, Newport, RI, slate. Signed by John Stevens 111. An important signed portrait stone. (Box 1)
- Treat Family stone of the 1790's in East Glastonbury, CT, redstone. The ne-classical profile device became popular in East and South Glastonbury after ca. 1790 but is seen not at all in Glastonbury itself or across the river in Wethersfield. (Box 1)
- Noah Andrus stone, 1780, redstone, Farmington, CT. A late example of portrature in the ne-classical style popular in the lower Connecticut River Valley area between Farmington and Meriden, CT. This a particular well preserved example. (Box 1)
- Daniel Grindley stone, 1781, Farmington, CT, redstone. Neo-classical profile portrait style. (Box 1)
- Nathaniel Morton stone, 1776, Plymouth, MA, slate. Portratit stone showing effigy of deceased appearing over a brick tomb. A very unusual theme in New England. I have seen only one other example in the Sharon Connecticut area, and another variant much changed in Paxton, MA. The design may have been derived from a broadside. (Box 1)
- Detail of broadside cut for Reverend George Whitfield in 1771 and now in the Boston Public Library. (Box 1)
- Hannah Lewis stone, 1790, Plymouth, MA, slate. A late portrait stone from Plymouth showing the slipping of technique from provincial baroque imagery into crude copies of already diluted forms. (Box 1)
- Joanna Morton stone, 1818, Plymouth, MA, slate. A very late example of the Plymouth portrait style. Notice how the drapery has been understood in a ornamental rather than a representational manner and how the face reveals the double outline encountered only in ornamental art. A very important shift from a naturalistic style to an ornamental one. (Box 1)
- Captain Johyn Virgin stone, 1814, slate, 29 1/4 x 48 1/4. A late example of portrature showing the change of custome between the late 18th and early 19th century. Portraits of the 19th century are most rare. (Box 1)
- Mary Cutler stone, 1703, Charlestown, MA, slate, 21 x 22 3/4. A deeply cut stone in the manner of the provincial baroque. Attributted to Joseph Lamson of the Charlestown, MA. The emergence of the angel or soul-angel in the central lunnette of the stone markes the transformation from 17th to 18th century iconography which emphasized the joys of Resurrection rather than terrors of death. The stone is the earliest dated example of an angel in the central lunette in Greater Boston. (Box 1)
- Captain John Fowle stone, 1711, Charlestown, MA, slate, 24 x 25.5. Attributed to Joseph Lamson of Charlestown. Example of armorial stone. (Box 1)
- John Lee stone, 1761, Concord, MA, slate. Example of the transition from the provincial baroque style to the ornamental. The volutes, columns, and acantlus-like designs are all derived from the normative forms of the baroque, but have begun to flatten out in the hands of a rural carver. (Box 1)
- James Hickox stone, 1725, Durham, CT,19 x 28, redstone. An example of the early Connecticut Valley. Stone with simple rosettes topping both border panels. Similar stones can be found as far south as about Milford and as far north as Northampton, MA during the 1720's. (Box 1)
- Joseph Hickox stone, 1725, Durham, CT, redstone 22 3/4 x 26 1/4. Between 1725 and 1730 highly ornamented stone begin to appear in the burial grounds of the Connecticut Valley. This example shows the coil volute border panel which may have been derived from the New london carvers or simplified from Boston examples. The winged death's head was almost certainly taken from a Boston stone. Similar stones may be found throughot the Connecticut Valley after 1730. (Box 1)
- Oren Alley stone, 1822, Durham, CT, marble. Example of the neo-classical mode of carving which superceded stones cut in the older manner after about 1800. (Box 1)
- Olive Storrs stone, 1783, Storrs, CT, Granite. Attributed to the Manning Family. Winged effigy beginning to turn into pure ornament by opening up the feathering of the wings between foreground and background, to create the illusin of tendrils rather than a fully feathered wings, or wings. (Box 1)
- Pliny Dwight stone, 1783, Belchertown, MA. 21.5 x 28.5. Soul-effigy surrounds by an arbor of grapes. Attributed to the Sikes family. (Box 1)
- Agigail Barber stone, 1797, Hebron, CT, marble, 20 1/4 x 36.5. Transitional stone between older baroque tri-partite form and newer square topped neo-classical stones. (Box 1)
- Katharin Ayers stone, 1684, Newport, RI. Attributed to Williams Mumford of Boston, MA. Example of the diffusion of the Boston style to Newport, RI in the late 17th century. Notice the angel at the botom of the stone. By the 18th century the winged angel would replace the central death's head at the top of the stone. (Box 1)
- Deborah Thomas stone, 1696, Marshfield, MA., slate. A very early example of the winged angel theme being used in the central lunette of the stone in the place of the more common death head. The stone is attributed to "J.N." of Boston, MA (Box 1)
- Isabella Tawley stone, 1737, Marblehead, MA, slate. 17th century stone probably re-cut with 18th century inscription. Death and time appear on the border panels. Mentioned in Dissertation. (Box 1)
- Lieut. Jabez Smith stone, 1780, The Granary, Boston, MA., slate. One of the few New England stone to show a ship. There is a similar example in Groton, CT. The inscriptio reads, "Anchored in the haven of rest." (Box 1)
- Joseph Reynolds stone, 1759, Bristol, RI. An armorial stone of a type popular in Rhode Island, although such designs were more often found on tombs than on upright gravestones. (Box 1)
- Michael Wigglesworth stone, 1705, Malden, MA, slate. This example of a Greater Boston stone was cut for one of the most famous Ministers in New England showing that at death few had any reservations about using carved imagery on the stones of those dear to them. (Box 1)
- Colonel Seth Pomroy stone, 1777, Northampton, MA., redstone. Two Trumpeting Archangels hold up a crown with a Cross set upon it. This is the most obvious use of the Cross in all Protestant New England. (Box 1)
- Bellows children, 1799, Rockingham, VT., slate. This small stone shows the final phase of the ornammental rural style in New England which replaced the seen world with a conceptual one made up of almost wholly geometric forms. Notice, for example, how the bodies are formed of half-circles and ornamented with a simple checkboard design while the hair is formed of links and the circular head rests upon the trunk without the support of a neck which in representational art would be taken for granted. (Box 1)
- Detail of Bellows children. (Box 1)
- English Broadside elegy from the late 17th century showing a royal funeral. The garp of the horses and the hearse were in many ways similar to those used in New England, no engravings of American funerals of the 17th century exist. (Box 1)
- An English Broadside of the 17th century. See plates 125 and 126 in Dissertation for comparisons. (Box 1)